[Music]
for
live
thank you for
coming very
sad then I got uh slowly two other phone
calls one
brother and
[Music]
then I almost went crazy landed in
new and that was like
and very bad at that
time very very
dangerous I I fought my way through the
crowd I went to a
hotel and uh I hit
him
1,000
guys then after 3 weeks you are finished
yellow now
you're and you are supposed to relax for
the rest of your
life drink butter
tea and sometimes taste a little
M sometimes taste a little baby
m
[Music]
then uh but my teacher called
me then he said uh you are the first
white guy in 600 years to finish the
dish in our so I got for $10 the
suit and the first summer I wore the
whole same suit every
day and
I and secretly I'm trying to use karma
in
and uh now that when when I finished it
was $100 million 1999 thank
you time so then um I don't know one
company book
company they asked me can you write a
book about
that that's called
Diamond and now that book has spread to
many countries
I heard in China
[Music]
people I think everybody in the world
wants three different
[Music]
things uh they want
money enough money to be comfortable
and don't worry about credit
C we have a nice
home have a nice
car go for vacation if your energy
is you don't have
strength
energy if you don't feel
young then it doesn't help to have
money you feel
tired and some people are lucky they get
all three
things they get
money good
family and they
have I like
[Music]
I
then
uh Superman Superman Super Woman super
Transformers X-Men X-Men
greenen
anyway why do people make those
movies because all of us we are
Anonymous small
people we don't have any
super
but we all want
it how to use Karma to find a nice
[Music]
partner we will talk about that and and
the
system the
method if you understand
it if you have
it you can have the work
you become like
Spiderman that that understanding
another will make you
spider you don't have to get bit by
spider so these two
nights you will learn something
precious at your
job then's job is
what uh in English they call hunter
[Music]
gatherer and uh you can find not a lot
you can find one one one plant here one
plant
there each plant has maybe 10 pieces of
rice so the whole
day he is looking for
rest one One stock by one stock one
piece by one
piece then he takes 10
grand he keeps it in his
hand if he finds
enough they will
[Music]
have if he doesn't
find because they always eat immediately
what they
have they don't have
because he can find
enough one day he doesn't find enough
for three four five
days they will die and this is the old
way I find some easier
food dinosaur goes
away look he has to look for the r
but it got covered by
dir he finds a few
[Music]
pieces then he comes home
to to the
cave where's the
honey oh I got in a fight with the
dinosaur and we had a big fight I almost
died
honey I only have a few
pieces yeah yeah you went to the bar
with your
[Music]
[Applause]
friend uh three months
[Music]
pass and uh is coming
one he
they he's looking at the life then
uh then he did something which is more
intelligent than Einstein
[Music]
he he said this is where I I dropped the
last and we covered we covered it with
dirt it
ran three months went
by now I have 10 times
[Music]
my first time he has more than one
hand then then you know how that light
goes off in the head
thing he has an idea he gets excited he
takes all the
rice he puts it in his like I don't
know runs for he calls his
wife come to the said what are you
doing you have to eat it no no I have a
better
idea she hit him
again then 3 months
pass
look then she
says the wife didn't change for 12,000
years she says I told
you and
uh this is the invention of farming Sam
I'm Sasha
and
[Music]
all it's a big
buddh and the Friday evening is also
holy time
[Music]
right so both are coming together this
year
security and they check me and
everything then then I walk a little
further I come out to this huge uh
Square
and you're the only person in Israel who
doesn't
know you know I watched it for several
hours I would like to talk about an idea
like
that uh right
now we wake
up in the morning
every then we we walk through New York
or we walk through t
[Music]
we are looking for R you don't know if
the doctor will tell you her cancer
today or
not and we live like K
now just
looking maybe I will find something and
maybe
not and maybe I will die
today this
is you don't have to go wondering in the
forest more looking and
hoping what you
want
just and
relax okay like he he learned how to
[Music]
trans then he goes inside and
watches he doesn't have to go
W into the
forest because that creates
[Music]
anxiety possible to just trans
it and
relax is it possible we can have an
evolution
similar will
[Music]
come it's a different
syst is the most famous from
[Music]
India saw today with his beautiful
son and I was there when he was started
almost anyway it's
painless finish half
hour really I feel very
[Music]
strong
fore
for
okay that you have to
know uh if you want to learn how to
farm uh
money money or
partner or husband
upgrade improve your
husband I don't mean another husband I
mean improve your
[Music]
husband then uh there's one idea you
have to
know so this is the most important part
of the five days we are here
[Music]
in this is an the Tibetan way of
teaching
uh in the in
tiet and so I'm going to ask some
questions youbody have some
R they don't want the front world
doesn't want
it uh later later
okay that's too big
okay just destroy in the mon they
destroy
it
uh so I will I will ask a
question then you have to answer
okay only the people in the front row
have to be
nerves uh what is this
thing okay who's not
answering stand up this a something too
true next
question who's correct the person or the
[Music]
do you can say both I think
so the human will say don't Che on the
pen you are ruining
it the dog will say you are a fool you
don't have to write without that
you
so both are
correct now most important
question if I put this thing
here then all the people go out of the
room and all the dogs go out of the
room and the room is
empty at that
time is it a pen or is it
a you can say none I
think say neither
so in Buddhism there's this idea of
emptiness many people
misunderstanding uh my
teacher uh when I first came to the
monastery he the first day he took me to
a small
room you can hold your arms like
this you can touch the
walls this way
no heat no no
cooling then the bed is for to vetan
person I have to sleep like
this then uh nowaday people give me a
big
bed but I still have to sleep like this
you know so then he said you will
meditate
[Music]
here you will sit here on the floor
and you will
meditate then he said do you know how to
meditate I said I know I know I
know I read a book about
it in America you know then they said do
you know about
emptiness yeah yeah I know I know I
know later he gave me a new
name Mr I know I
know
I said okay I will he said I will go
upstairs when I ring the
bell then you should come and tell me
how is your
meditation so I I sit down to
[Music]
meditate then you knock on the
door show means come come but it's the
word you use for
then you come in then uh you have to
into bed you have to go down on your
knees and I don't know why you have to
go like this you're not supposed to look
at the
teacher you're supposed to look at the
floor then you have to
go that shows respect I don't know
why yes
yes and he said said did you
meditate
yes what did you meditate
about
emptiness what is
emptiness close your
eyes think about black black everything
black he said oh that's very
interesting you
are I said Lama what does mean
Koopa KOA is
idiot then you go
again you try again then I will ring it
down I went
downstairs then I close my eyes like
that hold the
hand that you're supposed to go like
this with your
eyes
when I start to think about
something I try to stop
it every time I think about
something I try to stop this this should
be
emptiness
then I have to run
upstairs come
[Music]
down what
is I know I
know then what is it close your
eyes think about
nothing then he said what is the meaning
of
meditation you are focusing the Mind
method so you are thinking very clearly
about
something yes so your
meditation you are thinking very hard
about not
thinking he
said
oh Lama what is
sh big
idiot you try
again then I go
downstairs try to
meditate nothing good nothing
bad everything is
illusion nothing is
real if someone kisses
you don't be happy if someone hits
you don't be
unhappy just
neutral with
everything nothing is me then I went up
ding D ding ding
[Music]
ding what is
emptiness everything is
uded nothing's
good nothing's
bad this said that is
sh what is
sh super
IDI super
ID then you know many many hundreds of
years people don't
understand uh what is
emptiness they think close her
eyes everything's black like the like
out
space or uh don't think about
anything or everything is
illusion it's all
wrong that's all
wrong why they can't help
you your
goals Financial
independent uh good partner good good
health peaceful world
those three don't help
you think about
nothing then I don't think money will
come okay uh you
know everything is black black
black I don't think you will attract a
partner okay so
this I put this thing
here all the people go
up all the bgs go
out that one can help
you at that time it's not a
pen and it's not a
true okay last thing before the
break why can it help
you how does it help you to get those
things I'll ask you another
question listen
carefully next 5 minutes okay after that
can
sleep I was spoken many many countries
but Shanghai was the best
[Music]
one in China you're not allowed to run
the air
conditioning until the theater reaches
45 C
something so I was soaking hot you and
Paul first world fell
asleep like this each one is SLE
[Music]
here so stay away for 5
minutes this is the most important
part uh
question is the pen coming from
me or is the pen coming from the
P which
one it's must be coming from
me why because the dog doesn't see them
if the pen is coming from the
pen then the dog will try to write
something because he will see the the
pen is talking I'm a pen I'm a
pen then the dog will try to write
something I think a
poem to his dog
girlfriend you have a
nice but they don't they don't do that
it means the pen must be coming from my
mind now most important
question everybody we all understand
it's coming from my
mind can I close my
eyes and can I
wish or
pray or
want that it will be a big
diam if it's coming from my
[Music]
can I just think something
else positive
thinking I don't want 10 I want a big
diamond let's
try if I can make one I will split with
you
okay then I wish wish wish wish
wish you did this when you were a
child and you have the same
result
it's still a
pen this is very very
important it is coming from
me it's coming from my
mind but in this
moment I cannot control it and we say
the mind has a
seed there's a seed in the mind for a
pen and the dog doesn't have that seat
I have the
SE didn't pull something out of his
pocket like that slow
motion slow motion what is
this you're no then you're
M
we a seed opens in your
mind at that
second when I pull it up as my hand is
moving a seed is opening in your
mind and a small picture comes
out of the
sea that picture is made of
light it's
bright it's
luminous it's made of
FL that picture is coming out of your
mind
from a pen
seed and that my my hand is
moving and the seat is opening at the
same
moment because karma is unbelievably
complicated it it always matches second
by
second my hand is coming
up the seat is opening the picture is
the light picture of light of a pen
comes out of
the when G Michael's hand
stops the picture the picture comes out
of the
mind and it and it comes on this
thing and then it's a
pen it wasn't a pen right before we came
[Music]
in I I went like this and in your mind
the SE is opening at the same
time the timing matches
perfectly it's the miracle of
Karma and then I see
him then I make a
mistake I believe it was always a
p but it wasn't before I came in before
I pulled it out it wasn't a
pen my mind made a picture and made it a
pen that picture is coming from a seed
in my
mind how do you put the seed in your
mind for
pen one week
before you find somebody who needs a
pen when the pen touches his
hand and I let go and I give him the pen
it put a seed
in then after that seed Cooks in my mind
for one
week one week
later and
it's everything's the
same
money the peace or lack of peace in the
[Music]
world coming from
me from SE in my
mind if I can teach you how to plant a
different
seed you can be like and
book you don't have to go looking around
for
money just plant it relax money will
come husband will
change I'm not kidding You Can Have
Anything You Can Have
Anything peace also comes
back so uh after the
bread we will start uh four
[Music]
steps uh I think it's good that you're
choos one saying that
[Music]
you
tonight and and then you do an
experiment you see if it
works you try these four
steps and you see if it
works I just somebody who
lonely give
them we'll talk about that more
tomorrow but I'm happy to say she's
getting married next week
[Music]
she she she really did
it so you choose what you
want just one
thing and let's do an
experiment you cannot plant a SE
byself you cannot se
byself you need another
person it's like you cannot put
watermelon
seed here on the
stage the SE
is you
want you
another it's not possible
to
[Music]
so let
say then I say I will help
you I will give you some money to
[Music]
start I put the money in his
hand when I let
go that's seed will grow every
day then it
opens as a as an image of
light and that comes out of my
way as
new as my
new everything is coming like
[Music]
that I want part
uh I'm living
alone I must find another person who is
know I
like I have my own
person before I came here today I went
to the
Z to buy her some
clothing she's 86 years old
every time I go to another country I buy
something then when I come home to see
her I had my arm right
there she's how are
you then I said oh I have a gift for
you then she pretends to be
surprised she
oh oh
[Music]
when I when I give the lonely person a
gift I give her like a bouse I
give I go like to Starbucks what you
call him
arafe
[Music]
then I sit
down
one you will
find but you didn't
[Music]
find you don't have to look in all
the
like okay just plant
it give give give give to the
[Music]
person and then and then he will come
because he's coming from your
mind by the
way people ask
me if it's coming from my
mind it's not
real I want to